二零零九年，普通高等学校招生。
全国统一考试听力部分，
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案。
转涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
试音到此结束，听力考试正式开始。
请看听力部分。
本第一节，第一节，听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后。
你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题，
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容。
你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案标在试卷上。
衬衫。
的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择
项，并将其标在试卷上。
现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容
I'd like to stay two nights, please.
you want full board or half board?
What's the difference?
Full board includes all meals, and half board includes just breakfast and dinner.
Shouldn't we invite Cathy to the party tonight?
Invite Cathy? She is the one who's planning the whole thing.
Text 4. Did you say you were driving to town this morning?
Yes, I have to draw some money from the bank to pay my bookstore bills.
Text 5. What are you working on so hard?
An article for the newspaper.
If I'm late, it won't get printed until next week.
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下面五段对话或独白。
每段对话或独白后有几个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或读。
读白，读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六和第七两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Text 6. Excuse me, I think you're in my seat.
Sorry, but it says 7A on my boarding card.
Oh, right. I asked for a window seat, you see?
Yeah, so did I.
What's your seat number?
Let's see. Oh, it's 8A.
So I guess you're in the seat behind me.
Oh, yes. Sorry about that.
Excuse me, I think you're in my seat.
Sorry, but it says 7A on my boarding card.
Oh, right. I asked for a window seat, you see?
Yeah, so did I.
What's your seat number?
Let's see. Oh, it's 8A.
So I guess you're in the seat behind me.
Oh, yes. Sorry about that.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至十小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Text 7. Can I help you?
Yes, how much are these t -shirts?
They're $12.50 each.
I like the green one, but it isn't big enough.
Have you got a larger size?
Just a minute.
No, I'm sorry, we haven't.
What about the black one?
No, it's too dark.
I'd prefer something lighter, yellow or pink.
How about the pink one?
Yes, that's nice.
I'll take it.
That's $12.50 then, please.
Here you are.
Can I help you?
Yes, how much are these t -shirts?
They're $12.50 each.
I like the green one, but it isn't big enough.
Have you got a larger size?
Just a minute.
No, I'm sorry, we haven't.
What about the black one?
No, it's too dark.
I'd prefer something lighter, yellow or pink.
How about the pink one?
Yes, that's nice.
I'll take it.
That's $12.50 then, please.
Here you are.
听下面一段对话，回答第十一至十三小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Text 8. So, how long have you been living in London?
Er, a couple of years.
How long have you been working here?
Only a few months.
I moved down here for the job.
There was no work for me where I came from.
Where did you come from then?
I came from a small village called Arnside, near Lancaster a year ago.
Um, there was nothing to do there, so I moved to London.
Do you enjoy working here in this restaurant?
Very much so.
So, how long have you been living in London?
Er, a couple of years.
How long have you been working here?
Only a few months.
I moved down here for the job.
There was no work for me where I came from.
Where did you come from then?
I came from a small village called Arnside, near Lancaster a year ago.
Um, there was nothing to do there, so I moved to London.
Do you enjoy working here in this restaurant?
Very much so.
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至十七小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
咦？
Text 9. I'm sure you've noticed a lot of things that are different about our school.
Oh yes. In the United States, we don't have to carry a big school bag with us like
you do. Why is that?
We have a locker of our own, which is a small box with a lock.
We keep textbooks and our personal things in it.
I just bring a day pack to school.
A day pack?
Yes, it's a small bag that you carry on your back.
What do you carry in it?
My notebooks or a few books for homework.
That's convenient. Is there anything else you've noticed about our school?
Yes, I am surprised that everyone is so silent in class.
What do mean?
Well, we usually ask questions about exams, homework or textbooks on the first day
of the school year.
The teacher likes such questions.
So you felt it different?
Yes. I expected to see a lot of discussions in class, because we learn that way in
the United States.
I see. That'll be a good topic for our school newspaper for the first month of the
term. Nice talking with you.
See you around.
Bye. I'm sure you've noticed a lot of things that are different about our school.
Oh yes. In the United States, we don't have to a big school bag with us like you do.
Why is that?
We have a locker of our own, which is a small box with a lock.
We keep textbooks and our personal things in it.
I just bring a day pack to school.
A day pack?
Yes, it's a small bag that you carry on your back.
What do you carry in it?
My notebooks or a few books for homework.
That's convenient. Is there anything else you've noticed about our school?
Yes, I am surprised that everyone is so silent in class.
What do mean?
Well, we usually ask questions about exams, homework or textbooks on the first day
of the school year.
The teacher likes such questions.
So you felt it different?
Yes. I expected to see a lot of discussions in class, because we learn that way in
the United States.
I see. That'll be a good topic for our school newspaper for the first month of the
term. Nice talking with you.
See you around.
Bye. everybody. Today for our writing class, we are glad to have Mr.
听下面一段对话，回答第十八至二十小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Henry Stone with us, a well -known writer in this country.
He's going to share with us his writing experiences.
Now, Henry, please tell us how you find so many interesting things for your stories.
OK. I watch people a lot.
I do that when I travel.
I've been to many countries such as Italy and Sweden.
So I spend a lot of time at airports.
While waiting for my flights, I watch people passing by and start my imagination.
For example, the other day when I was waiting for my flight to Greece, I saw a
couple. They were buying magazines at that moment.
They were not wearing business clothes, but the man was carrying a suitcase.
Every few seconds, the woman looked around.
I wondered if someone was following them.
Perhaps they were running away and...
You know, this reminded me of a story in the newspaper that day.
A bank clerk stole one million pounds a week before and disappeared with his wife.
There was a picture of them in the paper.
The couple really looked like the thieves.
Maybe I should stop them.
Just then, I saw them say goodbye to each other and the woman walked away.
Well, sometimes I make mistakes like that.
But I find things like that very useful for my writing.
Good morning, everybody.
Today for our writing class, we are glad to have Mr.
Henry Stone with us, a well -known writer in this country.
He's going to share with us his writing experiences.
Now, Henry, please tell us how you find so many interesting things for your stories.
Okay. I watch people a lot.
I do that when I travel.
I've been to many countries such as Italy and Sweden.
So I spend a lot of time at airports.
While waiting for my flights, I watch people passing by and start my imagination.
For example, the other day when I was waiting for my flight to Greece, I saw a
couple. They were buying magazines at that moment.
They were not wearing business clothes, but the man was carrying a suitcase.
Every few seconds, the woman looked around.
I wondered if someone was following them.
Perhaps they were running away and...
You know, this reminded me of a story in the newspaper that day.
A bank clerk stole one million pounds a week before and disappeared with his wife.
There was a picture of them in the paper.
The couple really looked like the thieves.
Maybe I should stop them.
Just then, I saw them say goodbye to each other and the woman walked away.
Well, sometimes I make mistakes like that.
But I find things like that very useful for my writing.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案转涂到客观。
题答题卡上。
Thank you for watching.
Thank you. you
听力部分到此结束。